Luke Belliveau

Software Engineer

USA, Hungary lukebelliveau.dev github.com/lukebelliveau hi@lukebelliveau.dev +1-617-275-2452 Luke is a product-focused engineer with seven years of experience engineering full stack web applications and services at enterprise scale. He specializes in full-stack solutions with unique and complex UI requirements.

Tools -

Languages & Databases TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, Java, Python, Golang, C#

Databases PostgreSQL, Firebase Realtime DB, MongoDB, Cassandra

Deploy, Automation, Hosting AWS, Digital Ocean, Firebase, Jenkins, Spinnaker, GitHub Actions, Vercel

Web Frameworks & Build Tooling React, Next.js, Redux, Vite, Auth0, Konva, Highcharts

Testing Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Vitest, Cypress, Jest,

JUnit, Chai / Mocha, Selenium

Work Experience

Consultant Software Engineer NuWave Technologies

2021 - Current

Luke managed the development and maintenance of NuWave's suite of web applications. With NuWave, he:

- Led development of the Prizm API Gateway management console on a team of three developers to a successful launch, built on Jenkins/AWS EC2 and deployed to AWS S3
- Engineered a seamless migration from AngularJS to React for NuWave's LightWave Client and Server products, reducing total lines of source code by 35%. Built with Vite.
- Created new automated testing pipelines and ran workshops & training, facilitated a culture of testing & CI, building up company-wide front-end code coverage from 0% to over 95% with Vitest, Jest and Cypress
- Played an instrumental role in the interview, evaluation & mentorship process of new hires

Technical Partner ZUUT.co 2020 - Current

Luke collaborated with ZUUT's founder, working from the product's inception through a successful launch. Handling all facets of development, he:

- Designed and implemented a deep interaction & collision detection engine, handling the various states & behaviors of 100+ items painted on the browser's canvas, managed with Redux & synced to Firebase Realtime DB
- Implemented an interface for nontechnical employes to edit and publish item data for the 500+ interactive items in the application
- Designed and implemented an account and data management system using Firebase services such as Authentication, Realtime DB and Cloud Storage
- Implemented system & interface for users to compare, contrast and purchase equipment for their grow designs featuring an affiliate link system using Amazon's APIs, successfully qualifying ZUUT for Amazon's Associate's Program
- Integrated content management systems enabling nontechnical users to create & update blog content with a simple interface and Contentful integration

On Grubhub's Cloud Infrastructure team, Luke designed & implemented frameworks, tools, & services that enabled web, mobile, & site reliability engineers to do their jobs as efficiently as they can. In his time at Grubhub, he:

- Ownership of Notifications stack of microservices in Java (with Guice & Spring), spanning SMS, mobile push, email, & fax functionalities for Grubhub's 521,000 Daily Active Users
- Engineered changes to core Java framework to facilitate communication between microservices in a new Envoy service mesh architecture
- Led integration of SMS service with a new provider, handling the development, evaluation, & communication with stakeholders
 on both ends
- Built a service in React & Python used by Site Reliability Engineers to view system status & make changes during outages
- Designed the architecture & database schemas for a new notifications platform. This service was used by product & marketing teams at Grubhub to manage notifications for email, SMS, push, & fax.

Senior Software Engineer

Thoughtworks

2017 - 2018

As a Senior Engineer at ThoughtWorks, Luke worked on software teams servicing clients in e-commerce & cybersecurity. In this role, Luke:

- Built a dashboard for analysts to monitor web traffic with rich interactions and data visualizations, built with Vue & Highcharts
- Facilitated front-end training sessions for the company, coordinating speakers & workshops for bimonthly meetups in a global community of React & Vue developers
- Designed APIs & data pipelines to facilitate a seamless integration of Kroger's e-commerce platform with a newly acquired subsidiary
- Worked with designers & executive stakeholders to determine key features/specifications & break them into manageable tasks
- Developed a backend-for-frontend in Golang to aggregate, analyze & perform transformations on repositories of logs before serving them to the client, improving performance

Associate Software Engineer ThoughtWorks

2016 - 2017

Luke began his career as an Associate Software Engineer at ThoughtWorks, where he was deployed on a software delivery team at one of the largest health insurance firms in the United States. In this role, his achievements include:

- Delivered a full-stack health insurance portal in JavaScript, React+Redux and Java
- Serving as a front-end specialist, participating in architecture meetings & facilitating weekly discussions about React & JavaScript topics
- Mentoring new hires, providing weekly office hours & coaching sessions

Freelance Projects

https://selenium.dev

2019

Given a set of mockups, I delivered a new website for Selenium, a popular browser automation tool. Built with Jekyll & Hugo.

Devil's Dice Game 2018

Devil's Dice is an exciting mobile game where users place a phone on the table & face various challenges based on a virtual dice roll. This app has a special place in my heart - a year after its release, I noticed a group of travelers playing the game in the kitchen at a hostel in Slovakia! It remains active today & enjoys a 4.5-star rating on the Google Play Store with over 10,000 downloads.

SATURATION - BROCKHAMPTON

2017

Official application for world-famous boyband BROCKHAMPTON, designed to release music videos & other exclusive goodies before their general release to external platforms. With over 10,000 downloads, SATURATION enjoyed a rating of 5 stars on the Google Play store, where it was active from 2017-2019.

Education